<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="goterm_joseki">Joseki jōseki (定石?) are established sequences of play which
        (locally speaking) are
        considered to give an optimal result to both players. There are thousands of such lines that
        have been
        researched and documented.
        \nOften joseki are played out early in the game and involve dividing the corners. There are
        also \"mid-game
        joseki\", dealing with for example an invasion into a common enclosure or framework.
        \nThough joseki have some parallel with chess openings, they differ significantly. Chess
        openings structure the
        whole board while joseki deal only with a local position. Therefore the choice of which
        joseki (of many
        possible) to play in any given situation should be based on an assessment of the global
        position. This includes
        considerations of the direction of play, current balance of territory and influence, and
        one\'s own game
        strategy.
        \nIt is also quite possible to deviate from joseki and obtain a good result if the
        surrounding position allows.
        In other words, joseki are sensitive to the context in which they are played.
        \n\nhttp://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_terms#Joseki
    </string>

    <string name="goterm_miai">Miai (見合い) in Go are, in the simplest terms, a pair of vacant points
        on the board that
        are equivalent in terms of value. For example, if Black plays at A, White can play at B and
        suffer no
        disadvantage from the exchange.
        \nThis occurs often. With respect to a group\'s development or survival, pairs of points are
        frequently seen,
        such that if one player occupies one of them, his opponent will occupy the other. Miai can
        be seen in the fuseki
        stage on a large scale, or in a simple life and death problem, such as a straight four-space
        eye. This shape is
        alive because of its two central points a and b: if White plays b, Black can answer with a
        and vice versa.
        \nThe term originates from the Japanese custom of arranging marriage through a series of
        meetings (miai) to view
        prospective spouses (見る miru, \"view\", 合う au, \"meet\").
        \n\nhttp://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_terms#Miai
    </string>

    <string name="goterm_shape">Shape is the configuration of stones in terms of their flexibility
        and efficiency at
        staying connected, forming eyes, and maintaining liberties. Stones are said to have good
        shape if they are
        efficient and flexible, or bad shape if they are inefficient. Classic examples of good shape
        are the ponnuki
        (four stones in a diamond created by capturing an enemy stone) and the bamboo joint (a 2x3
        pattern of two
        stones, two spaces and two more stones). Examples of bad shape are the empty triangle (three
        adjacent stones
        forming an \'L\') and the dango (large clump of stones not containing any eyes). Joseki is
        in large part the
        study of forming good shape with your stones.
        \n\nhttp://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shape_(Go)
    </string>

    <string name="goterm_tesuji">A Japanese term used in the games of go or Shogi. A tesuji (手筋) is
        a clever play, the
        best play in a local position, a skillful move. Tesuji is derived from suji (筋), which means
        \"line of play\".
        \nThe opposite of tesuji is zokusuji, which can be translated as \"crude line of play\", and
        also referred to as
        anti-suji, or a vulgar move depending on the situation.
        \nTesuji is one of the important aspects of the game in which a player exerts his or her
        ability to \"read
        ahead\". In the game of Go, they are used in life and death situations (tsumego), in order
        to obtain initiative
        (sente), to capture stones, to gain extra points in the yose, or to otherwise save a
        seemingly unfavorable
        situation.
        \n\nhttp://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tesuji
    </string>

</resources>